Register of the Constantin W. Boldyreff papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Constantin W. Boldyreff papers
1878-2001
1910-1995
96012
Hoover Institution Archives
29 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (12.0 linear feet)
The collection consists of speeches and writings, correspondence, radio scripts, identification documents, biographical data, printed matter, sound recordings, and photographs relating to the settlement of displaced persons at the end of World War II, Russian émigré affairs, communism and conditions in the Soviet Union, and activities of the Narodno-Trudovoi Soiuz and other anti-communist organizations.
Boldyreff, Constantin W., 1909-1995.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1996.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Constantin Boldyreff (1910-1995) was born in Gatchina, not far from St. Petersburg. After the Russian revolution in 1917, he emigrated with his mother to China and then Yugoslavia, where he studied at the Russian Cadet School in Sarajevo. In 1935, he graduated from the University of Belgrade with a degree in engineering and worked for British and American mining companies in Yugoslavia.
As a university student, Boldyreff joined the newly formed émigré anticommunist party, the Narodno-Trudovoi Soiuz (NTS) or National Alliance of Russian Solidarists. Its activities were directed against the communist regime in the Soviet Union.
At the beginning of World War II, Boldyreff joined the Yugoslav army. During the German occupation, which followed the Yugoslav army's capitulation, he was arrested twice by the Gestapo and taken as a slave laborer to Germany. He was able to escape from the labor camp. In 1944, he and other members of the NTS began underground anticommunist activity in the German-occupied territories of the Soviet Union.
After the leadership of the NTS was almost annihilated by the Gestapo, Boldyreff escaped to Austria and organized a work brigade composed of Russian refugees, including prisoners of war that had been brought to Germany as slave laborers.
The end of the war found the Boldyreff family and their fellow refugees escaping west from the approaching Soviet armies. The greatest threat these displaced persons faced was forcible repatriation, a fate suffered by more than two million Russian refugees, who were returned to the Soviet Union by the Allies. Boldyreff was able to save not only his group but also thousands of others threatened with repatriation and subsequent death or imprisonment in Soviet concentration camps. They found refuge in the American-occupied zone in the Mönchehof displaced persons (or DP) camp. Boldyreff was instrumental in making the camp economically self-sufficient, providing housing and schools and organizing religious and cultural activities. Fear of repatriation forced displaced people to emigrate as soon as possible from Europe. In 1947, after carefully researching the economic opportunities for educated professionals, Boldyreff arranged for the Mönchehof group of DPs to emigrate to Morocco.
In 1947, the Boldyreff family emigrated to the United States, and Constatin Boldyreff was appointed as a professor at Georgetown University, where he established the Institute of Languages and Linguistics in the School of Foreign Service. Boldyreff continued his anticommunist activities on behalf of NTS, testifying before the Senate and House about conditions in the Soviet Union and advising the government on foreign policy. He made use of the American media to publicize his anticommunist campaign, publishing articles on political subjects in the American periodical press, addressing interested groups, and appearing on television.
He died in 1995.
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers of Constantin Boldyreff, founder and organizer of the Russian underground Natsional'no Trudovoi Soiuz (NTS), American professor, and former head of the Russian Department at Georgetown University School of Languages and Linguistics, consist of documents relating to the settlement of displaced persons at the end of World War II, Russian émigré affairs, communism and conditions in the Soviet Union, and activities of the Narodno-Trudovoi Soiuz and other anti-communist organizations.
The materials describing the history of Russian refugees in the post-World War II period can be found in ten series of the collection. The Biographical File and Family Files include identification documents, photographs, and memoirs. Correspondence and Speeches and Writings consist of Boldyreff's papers spanning the course of his career. A Subject File is arranged topically and contains materials documenting Boldyreff's work in specific capacites. Writings by Others include other Russian refugees' memoirs. The Oversize File consists of material that is distinctive because of its physical format. The Sound Recordings file includes sound tape reels documenting the activities of the organizations in which Boldyreff was involved.
Narodno-trudovoĭ soiuz.; Anti-communist movements.; International relief.; Refugees.; Soviet Union--Emigration and immigration.; Soviet Union.; World War, 1939-1945--Refugees.
- Biographical File, 1927-1995
  Scope and Contents note
  Consists of identification documents, immigration and travel papers, official files, and clippings. Arranged chronologically. See also: Family File and Oversize Materials.
  - Russkiĭ Kadetskiĭ Korpus: student report card, grade VI, 1927 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Transcription and certificate of completion Russian gymnasium in Yugoslavia, 1930 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Identification documents (IDs) issued in Yugoslavia, 1935-1942 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - IDs issued by German military government, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - IDs issued by United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - U.S. Embassy in Paris, applications for visa and travel documents, 1942-1947 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Copies of declassified material to prove the falsehood of accusations leveled against NTS and Boldyreff, 1945-1988 (Box-folder 1:7-8)
  - U.S. Department of State file, 1947-1989 (Box-folder 1:9-10)
  - U.S. immigration documents and passport, 1948-1986 (Box-folder 1:11-12)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation file, 1948-1990 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Clippings on Constantin Boldyreff, 1948-1995 (Box-folder 2:1-4)
  - Event logs and calling cards, 1950-1973 (Box-folder 2:5-12)
  - Biography, resume, and job applications, 1955-1976 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Travel documents, 1955-1978 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Central Intelligence Agency file, 1980-1990 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - The National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) Group Achievement Award to SAPSAT Team in recognition of the personal dedication, correspondence, certificate and photographs, 1983 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Obituaries and death certificate, 1995 (Box-folder 3:5-6)
    Includes sympathy correspondence, biographical writings, and clippings.
- Family File, 1887-2001
  Includes memoirs, photographs, genealogy charts, and clippings. Arranged in alphabetical order by family member names, then by physical form.
  - Boldyreff, Antonina (wife), 1941-2000
    - Passports and other identity documents, 1941-1995 (Box-folder 3:7-9)
    - Immigration file, 1948-1956 (Box-folder 3:10)
    - Correspondence, 1929-1997 (Box-folder 3:11-17, 4:1-4)
    - Career file, 1946-1979 (Box-folder 4:5-6)
    - Writings, circa 1955 (Box-folder 4:7)
    - Will, 1996 (Box-folder 4:8)
    - Obituary, 2000 (Box-folder 4:9)
      Includes photographs.
  - Boldyreff, Liubov' Vital'evna (mother), 1910-1933
    - Writings, 1910 (Box-folder 4:10)
    - Correspondence, 1927-1933 (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Boldyreff, Vasiliĭ Ceorgievich (father), 1917-1993
    - Military career file, 1917-1923 (Box-folder 4:12-13)
    - Clippings, 1921-1973 (Box-folder 4:14)
    - Correspondence, 1929-1933 (Box-folder 4:15)
    - Photographs, 1929-1933 (Box-folder 4:16)
      See also family photographs.
    - Political trial, copy of file from the Tsentral'nyi archiv, Moscow, 1933 (Box-folder 4:17)
    - Death certificate and other related documents, 1933-1992 (Box-folder 5:1)
    - Family memoirs of Vasiliĭ Boldyreff, circa 1990 (Box-folder 5:2)
  - Boldyreff (Semler), Helen (daughter), 1946-2001
    - Correspondence, 1946-1957, 1995 (Box-folder 5:3-9)
    - Travel and immigration documents, 1948-1956 (Box-folder 5:10)
    - Educational file, 1949-1955 (Box-folder 5:11-12)
    - Business reporter career file, including correspondence, clippings, and photographs, 1954-1962 (Box-folder 5:13)
    - Wedding clippings and photographs, 1957 (Box-folder 5:14-15)
    - White House interpreter career file, 1987-1996. (Box-folder 5:16-19)
      Includes protocol documents, photographs, correspondence, clippings, reports and other writings.
    - "A Tribute to My Father Constantine Boldyreff," and other family memoirs, 1995-2000 (Box-folder 6:1-6)
      Includes research materials and list of family papers given to the State Archives of the Russian Federation.
    - Obituaries, 2001 (Box-folder 6:7)
  - Stepanoff, Sergeĭ (half brother), drawings, memoirs by family member, and obituaries, 1919-1955 (Box-folder 6:8)
  - Stepanoff, Vsevolod (half brother), correspondence, 1932-1965 (Box-folder 6:9)
  - Zhigmanovskaia (Gigmanovskaia) Sofiia Nikolaevna (mother-in-law), 1887-1979
    - Birth and marriage certificates, 1887, 1904 (Box-folder 6:10)
    - Passports, and other identification documents, 1910-1974 (Box-folder 6:11)
    - Correspondence, 1921-1979 (Box-folder 6:12)
  - Zhigmanovskiĭ (Gigmanovsky), Aleksei Grigor'evich (father-in-law), 1912-1922
    - Curriculum vitae, 1912 (Box-folder 6:13)
    - Photographs, circa 1912 (Box-folder 6:14)
    - Letters to his wife Sofiia, 1919 (Box-folder 6:15)
    - Will, 1922 (Box-folder 6:16)
  - Family photographs, 1915-1995 (Box-folder 7:1-9)
    See also: Oversize Materials.
  - Genealogy charts, circa 1995 (Box-folder 7:10)
- Correspondence, 1930-1995.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - General, 1941-1994 (Box-folder 7:11-12)
  - America Illustrated, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 7:13)
  - Arsen'ev, Iuriĭ, 1964-1969 (Box-folder 7:14)
  - Artemov, Aleksandr, 1967-1984 (Box-folder 7:15)
  - Arutiunoff, A., 1960-1963 (Box-folder 7:16)
  - Berends, Alekseĭ E., 1963-1984 (Box-folder 7:17)
  - Bevad, Nikolaĭ, 1962-1969 (Box-folder 7:18-20)
  - Botian, Alex, 1965 (Box-folder 7:21)
  - Biuno, Boris, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 7:22)
  - Burkovskiĭ, Vasiliĭ, 1964 (Box-folder 7:23)
  - Chadsey, Carl T., 1959-1970 (Box-folder 7:24)
  - Cuddy, Edward, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 7:25)
  - Doubrovskiĭ, Veronika, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 7:26)
  - Drozdovskiĭ, Nikolaĭ, 1962-1968 (Box-folder 8:1-2)
  - Durocher, James L., 1962-1963 (Box-folder 8:3)
  - Elshner, Georgiĭ, K., 1922-1966 (Box-folder 8:4)
  - Emel'ianov, Dmitriĭ, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 8:5)
  - Fellers, Bonner, 1950-1956 (Box-folder 8:6)
  - Filimonov, Ivan K., 1955-1957 (Box-folder 8:7)
  - Fisher, Antony, 1953-1972 (Box-folder 8:8)
  - Fond Svobodnoĭ Rossii, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 8:9)
  - Garanin, Evgeniĭ, 1962-1969 (Box-folder 8:10-13)
  - Garaniny, Tat'iana and Irina, 1969-1993 (Box-folder 8:14-15)
  - Kennen, Andreĭ, 1964 (Box-folder 8:16)
  - Kharitonovskaia, Natal'ia, 1963 (Box-folder 8:17)
  - Kingsbery, Emily, 1963-1972 (Box-folder 8:18-19)
  - Kinsman, Warren J., 1952-1956 (Box-folder 8:210)
  - Kiselev, Aleksandr, 1970-1977 (Box-folder 8:21)
  - Kissinger, Henry A., 1962 (Box-folder 9:1)
  - Konstantinof, Dmitriĭ, Protoireĭ, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 9:2)
  - Korean Embassy, Washington, D.C., 1954 (Box-folder 9:3)
  - Kosovskiĭ (Kossovsky), Veniamin A., 1969 (Box-folder 9:4)
  - Krestinskaia, Mariia, 1962-1975 (Box-folder 9:5)
  - Krotkov-Sann, Christina, 1963 (Box-folder 9:6)
  - Kruschel, Sergei E., 1975 (Box-folder 9:7)
  - Kuznetsoff, Alekseĭ, 1959 (Box-folder 9:8)
  - Leetch, William D., 1956-1986 (Box-folder 9:9)
  - Levitskiĭ (Levitsky), Dimitriĭ A., 1994 (Box-folder 9:10)
  - MacDonald, Donald, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 9:11)
  - Manion, Clarence, 1954-1959 (Box-folder 9:12)
  - Moore, Frank M., 1954-1955 (Box-folder 9:13)
  - Nixon, Richard, 1961, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 9:14)
  - Norton, Rick, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 9:15)
  - Novoe Russkoe Slovo, 1950-1966 (Box-folder 9:16)
  - Paramonov, Boris M., 1977 (Box-folder 9:17)
  - Parkkali, Rudol'f, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 9:18)
  - Pearson, Frederick, 1953-1957 (Box-folder 9:19-20)
  - Petticrew, C. Richard, 1965-1981 (Box-folder 9:21)
  - Philibrick, Herbert A., 1963-1967 (Box-folder 9:22)
  - Pivkin, Vladimir, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 9:23)
  - Polchaninov, Rostislav, V., 1945-1965 (Box-folder 9:24)
  - Porenskiĭ, Vladimir D., 1952-1979 (Box-folder 10:1-10)
  - Rahr, Lev A., 1961-1979 (Box-folder 10:11-15)
  - Rauner, Ernst, Von, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 10:16)
  - The Reader's Digest, 1950-1970 (Box-folder 10:17-19)
  - Rebizov, S., 1967-1968 (Box-folder 10:20)
  - Reddaway, Peter, 1972 (Box-folder 10:21)
  - Romanov (Ostrovskiĭ), Evgeniĭ R., 1953-1989 (Box-folder 11:1-5)
  - Rostovtsev, Ivan, 1963 (Box-folder 11:6)
  - Rozhdestvenskiĭ (Rojdestvensky), Serafim, 1962-1969 (Box-folder 11:7-8)
  - Sander, Irina, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 11:9)
  - Sander, Sergeĭ, 1992 (Box-folder 11:10)
  - Semantsov, Iuriĭ, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 11:11)
  - Shul'gin, Dmitriĭ, 1970 (Box-folder 11:12)
  - Silvester, James, 1964 (Box-folder 11:13)
  - Slavinskiĭ, Mikhail and Tat'iana, 1965-1988 (Box-folder 11:14)
  - Stewart-Smith, D.G., 1965 (Box-folder 11:15)
  - Stolypin, Arkadiĭ Petrovich, 1969-1983 (Box-folder 11:16)
  - Sukov, Vasiliĭ, 1964 (Box-folder 11:17)
  - Swift, Caroline Hyde, 1963-1966 (Box-folder 11:18)
  - Troianov, Tikhon, circa 1955 (Box-folder 11:19)
  - Van'kov, Boris M., 1967 (Box-folder 11:20)
  - Vechesloff, Igor, 1959 (Box-folder 11:21)
  - Vorob'ev, Arkadiĭ, 1969 (Box-folder 11:22)
  - Voorhees, Coerte, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 11:23)
  - Watson, Thomas J., 1960 (Box-folder 11:24)
  - Webb, James, 1966 (Box-folder 11:25)
  - Wood, Robert E., 1954-1956 (Box-folder 11:26)
  - Zemels, Liudmila, 1963 (Box-folder 11:27)
  - Zeziulin, V., 1963-1965 (Box-folder 11:28)
  - Zhadan (Schadan), Pavel (Paul), 1965-1967 (Box-folder 11:29)
- Speeches and Writings, 1948-1971
  Includes correspondence, notes, memoranda, agenda, meeting and background materials, and press coverage. Arranged chronologically.
  - General, 1948-1979
    - Editorial correspondence and lecture contracts, 1949-1971 (Box-folder 12:1-15, 13:1-15)
    - List of Boldyreff's reference books, glossaries, and encyclopedias, compiled by Helen Boldyreff, 1996 (Box-folder 14:1)
    - Political jokes for speeches and articles, circa 1965 (Box-folder 14:2)
    - Newspaper articles, 1948-1979 (Box-folder 14:3-4)
  - "The story of one Russian underground organization attempting to overthrow Stalin," Look, 1948 (Box-folder 14:5)
  - "The Challenge of Russia's Underground," address, Women's Patriotic Conference, Washington, D.C. and Philadelphia, PA, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 14:6)
  - Articles and statements, Congressional Record, 1950-1970 (Box-folder 14:7-8)
  - "The True Face of Russian People,", 1950 (Box-folder 14:9)
  - "We Can Win the Cold War," Reader's Digest, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 14:10-15)
    Includes correspondence.
  - "Counterattack,", 1951 (Box-folder 14:16)
  - "Debates with Dr. Harry Schwartz,", 1951-1953 (Box-folder 14:17)
    Includes correspondence, notes, and clippings.
  - The Rotary Club Of Washington, speech, 1951 (Box-folder 14:18)
  - The Underground Is Fighting Stalin, 1951 (Box-folder 14:19)
  - "Is Revolution in Russia Possible?" address to the debates at The Economic Club of Detroit, 1952 (Box-folder 15:1)
  - Lecture delivered to Air War College on the subject of Special Operations, 1952 March 13 (Box-folder 15:2)
    Declassified U.S. government records, released July 2015.
  - "A Practical Experiment in Political Warfare," lecture at Conference on Communism, Ashridge, England, 1952 (Box-folder 15:3)
  - "The Obligation of Freedom in the Modern World," speech at Seccion de Problemas Contemporaneos, Menéndez Pelayo International University, Spain, 1952 (Box-folder 15:4)
    Includes clippings and photographs.
  - The Voice of the Russian Underground, 1952 (Box-folder 15:5)
  - "Soviet Underworld Task-Force Warning Cold War Up," lecture at the Air War College, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 15:6)
  - Address to the meeting of the Board of Directors of the National Chamber of Commerce at the Hotel Carlton, Washington, D.C., 1953 March 13 (Box-folder 15:7)
  - Whither the Red Army?, 1953 (Box-folder 15:8)
  - Du Pont Sales executives meeting, speech, Hershey, Pennsylvania, 1954 (Box-folder 15:9)
  - Life Officers Investment Seminar, speech, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 15:10-11)
  - "Communist World-Signs of Internal Tension,", 1954, 1965 (Box-folder 15:12)
  - "People's Resistance to Communism in Russia,", 1955 (Box-folder 15:13)
  - Hungarian revolution talks, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 15:14-15)
  - "The Lessons of Hungarian Revolt," address at sixty-sixth Continental Congress of National Society Daughters of the American Revolution, Washington, D.C., 1957 (Box-folder 16:1)
  - Soviet policies main talks, 1957-1964 (Box-folder 16:2-3)
  - "Victory of the Cross," lecture at Louisburg College, 1957 (Box-folder 16:4)
  - "We Still Can Save Peace,", 1957 (Box-folder 16:5)
  - "Should the United States Extend Aid To Communist Countries?," briefing session at the Educational Television and Radio Center, 1958 (Box-folder 16:6)
  - Radio address to the American Legion Division of Massachusetts, 1959 (Box-folder 16:7)
  - "Khrushchev and Summit Conference,", 1960 (Box-folder 16:8)
  - Russian Dictatorship Must Destroy Itself, 1960 (Box-folder 16:9)
  - Communism talks at Boston State Club, 1960 (Box-folder 16:10)
  - "How Do We Deal with Soviet Penetration in Latin America?," speech at Cosmos Club, Washington, D.C., 1961 (Box-folder 16:11)
  - "Rise, Culmination, and Decline of Communism in Russia," speech at seminar, Chicago-New York, 1961 (Box-folder 16:12)
  - "Russia and Africa,” seminar on Africa at New York State University, 1961 (Box-folder 16:13)
  - "To the Russian People from the American People," speech at the Project Alert School of Anti-Communism, Los Angeles, 1961 (Box-folder 16:14)
  - "Will the Future Belong to Communism?,", 1961 (Box-folder 16:15)
  - "The XXII Soviet Communist Party Congress and Its Political Implications,", 1962 (Box-folder 16:16)
  - "Possiiskaia emigratsia i NTS: obshchie zadachi," speech, New York, 1962 (Box-folder 17:1)
  - Vecher "GraneI'," speech, 1962 (Box-folder 17:2)
  - Speeches on communism, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 17:3)
  - "The Cross Versus the Hammer and Sickle,", 1965 (Box-folder 17:14)
  - "Voices of Revolt," lecture at Notre Dame College, Cleveland, Ohio, 1965 (Box-folder 17:5)
  - "Russia and China- The Great Conflict,", 1965-1968 (Box-folder 17:6-7)
  - "The New Emerging Russia,", 1965-1968 (Box-folder 17:8)
  - "World Communism,", 1968 (Box-folder 17:9)
  - "In Defense of Human Rights," petition to the United Nations, 1969 (Box-folder 17:10)
  - "The Soviet Union's Troubled Back-Yard,", 1969 (Box-folder 17:11)
  - "Bor'ba za veru i svobodu v Rossii i nashi real'nye vozmozhnosti sodeistviia ei," speech, Washington, D.C., 1971 (Box-folder 17:12)
  - Kadetskiĭ s"ezd, address, 1972 (Box-folder 17:13)
  - "Research and Development USA," exhibit script in Russian, 1972 (Box-folder 17:14-16)
    Includes original copy in English, correspondence, and contract.
  - "Twelve Years Since Stalin's Death,", 1973 (Box-folder 17:17)
  - "Den' neprimirimosti," speech, Organizatsiia Rossiiskikh Iunykh Razvedchikov, Washington, D.C., 1977 (Box-folder 18:1)
  - "Den' Generala P. N. Vrangelia," speech at anniversary meeting, Washington, D.C., 1978 (Box-folder 18:2)
  - "Menkhegof-lager' peremeshchennykh lits (Zapadnaia Germaniia),", 1986 (Box-folder 18:3)
    Includes drafts and correspondence.
  - Critique of Christopher Simpson's Blowback, book review, 1988 (Box-folder 18:4)
- Subject File, 1940-1995
  Arranged alphabetically
  - American Committee for the Liberation from Bolshevism, Inc, 1952-1954 (Box-folder 18:5)
  - American Friends of Russian Freedom, Inc., correspondence and newsletters, 1950-1953 (Box-folder 18:6)
  - Communist psychological warfare, 1950-1978
    Includes congressional records, correspondence, speeches and writings, clippings, and notes.
    - Congressional records on global propaganda war and psychological warfare, 1950-1978 (Box-folder 18:7-9)
    - Conference on Psychological Strategy at Washington, D.C., correspondence, speeches, and printed matter, 1952 (Box-folder 18:10)
    - "Psychological Warfare Manual," typescript, circa 1955 (Box-folder 18:11)
    - Comité international pour 1a défense des droits de l'homme, statements, appeals, reports, and correspondence, Paris, 1961-1972 (Box-folder 18:12-13, 19:1-2)
    - Printed matter, 1967-1975 (Box-folder 19:3-4)
  - Conference of National Organizations, Chicago, Illinois, correspondence, agenda, and business cards, 1952 (Box-folder 19:5)
  - Human Rights Organizations Briefings, Department of State, 1983 December 16 (Box-folder 19:6)
  - "Kongress Sootechestvennikov," program, correspondence, and printed matter, St. Petersburg, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 19:7-8)
  - Mönchehof Displaced Persons (DP) Camp, Germany, 1945-1948
    - Refugees issues documents, 1945 (Box-folder 19:9-10)
    - "Speech made by Mr. Boldyreff on December 30th, 1945 in Mönchehof to General Parker, Commander of the XXIIIrd Corps and the guests on the occasion of the opening of the exhibition reflecting the life and activities of the stateless working camps during the period from June 15th to December 15th, 1945," (Box-folder 19:11)
    - Petitions from the inhabitants to the Competent Authority of the American Expeditonary Forces in Germany in support of camp leader C. Boldyreff, 1945 (Box-folder 19:12)
    - Reports, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 19:13, 20:1-2)
    - Correspondence, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 20:3)
    - Operation Gold Cup, correspondence, memoirs, and photographs, 1945-1981 (Box-folder 20:4-5)
    - "Menkhegof," Boldyreff memoirs, circa 1950 (Box-folder 20:6-7)
    - Watercolor landscape paintings, circa 1950 (Box-folder 20:8)
    - "Menkhegof-lager' russkikh DiPi,"Tribukh, S.V., 1986 (Box-folder 20:9)
  - Morocco DP camp, 1946-1948
    - Planning and proposals, 1946-1948 (Box-folder 20:10-11)
    - Correspondence regarding resettlement activities, 1946-1948 (Box-folder 20:12-14)
    - Reports, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 20:15-16)
    - "Société Marocaine d'Etudes et de Prospection (A Realization of an Immigration Scheme for Displaced Persons on a Productive Self-Sufficient Basis), album, 1947 (Box-folder 21:1)
    - "The Morocco Story," Constantin Boldyreff memoirs, 1947 (Box-folder 21:2)
  - Narodno-Trudovoi Soiuz Rossiiskikh Solidaristov (The National Alliance of Russian Solidarists) (NTS), 1944-1989
    - Radio "Free Russia," correspondence, broadcasts, publicity materials, and leaflets, 1950-1970 (Box-folder 21:3-18, 22:1-2)
    - Programs, 1951-1972 (Box-folder 22:3-5)
    - Correspondence, 1944-1989 (Box-folder 22:6-17, 23:1-14)